Guide to the Herman F. Mark Collection RG.002
Poly Archives at the Bern Dibner Library of Science and Technology, NYU Libraries
- Series III: Writings
  - Subseries B: Speeches and Presentations
    - C.G. Overberger: Pioneer, Educator, Innovator, Administrator, Model, 1985; cuid2692 (Box 9, Folder 14)
    - Polymers of the 1980s: Familiar Concepts - New Vistas, undated; cuid2693 (Box 9, Folder 15)
    - New Concepts - New Polymers - New Applications, undated; cuid2694 (Box 9, Folder 16)
    - Oversize lecture drawings, undated; cuid2695 (Box 10, Item 1)
- Series IV: Publications
  - Subseries A: Publication lists, undated
    - Herman Mark publication lists, 1922-1992, undated; cuid2696 (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - Publications of H. Mark, undated; cuid2697 (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - Herman Mark OCLC holdings, 1986 June 20; cuid2698 (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - Lists of reports and books, undated; cuid2699 (Box 11, Folder 4)
    - Published Polymer Symposia lists, undated; cuid2700 (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - Supplements and addenda to publication lists, undated; cuid2701 (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Subseries B: Articles by Herman Mark
    - Über den Bau des kristallisierten Anteils der Cellulose II [The Structure of the Crystallized Components of Cellulose], 1928; cuid2702 (Box 11, Folder 7)
    - Ein Beitrag zur Konstitution der Stärke [Constitution of Starch]. Kurt Meyer, Heinrich Hopff, and Herman Mark, 1929; cuid2703 (Box 11, Folder 8)
    - Dir Stuktur der Zellulose und ihre technische Auswirkung [The Structure of Cellulose and its Technical Importance], 1929; cuid2704 (Box 11, Folder 9)
    - Vorgange bei der mechanischen Verformung von Kautschuk [Process of the Mechanical Deformation of Rubber]. Mark and Valko, 1930; cuid2705 (Box 11, Folder 10)
    - Phenomena of the Mechanical Deformation of Rubber, 1930, August-September; cuid2706 (Box 11, Folder 11)
    - Die Experimentellen und Theoretischen Grundlagen der Elaktronenbeugung, 1931; cuid2707 (Box 11, Folder 12)
    - Die Viskosität von Lösungen, Besonders von Lösungen Hochmolekularer Stoffe, 1933; cuid2708 (Box 11, Folder 13)
    - Zur innermolekularen Statistic, insbesondere bei Kettenmolekulen I, 1934 October 18; cuid2709 (Box 11, Folder 14)
    - Ergebnisse der Exakten Naturwissenschaften, 1936; cuid2710 (Box 11, Folder 15)
    - Die Elastizität Des Kautschuks und ihr Zusammenhang mit dem Strukturmodell, 1937; cuid2711 (Box 11, Folder 16)
    - Über die Entstehung und Eigenschaften Hochpolymerer Festkörper, 1937; cuid2712 (Box 11, Folder 17)
    - Ein Ausblick auf die Hochpolymere Chemie, 1938; cuid2713 (Box 11, Folder 18)
    - Fortschritte der Chemie organischer Naturstoffe, 1938; cuid2714 (Box 11, Folder 19)
    - Natural and Artificial Rubber: The Elasticity of Long - Chain Molecules, 1938; cuid2715 (Box 11, Folder 20)
    - Intermicellar Hole and Tube System in Fiber Structure, 1939; cuid2716 (Box 11, Folder 21)
    - Composite Elasticity of Rubber - I, 1940 June 1; cuid2717 (Box 11, Folder 22)
    - Elasticity of Natural and Synthetic Rubber, 1940; cuid2718 (Box 11, Folder 23)
    - Relation Between Chain Length Distribution Curve and Tenacity, 1941 July 17; cuid2719 (Box 11, Folder 24)
    - The Structure of Cellulose Fibers, 1941; cuid2720 (Box 11, Folder 25)
    - Structure and Mechanical Behavior of Highpolymers, 1941; cuid2721 (Box 11, Folder 26)
    - Some Applications of the Kinetic Theory to the Behavior of Long Chain Compounds, 1941; cuid2722 (Box 11, Folder 27)
    - Alkaline Purification of Cellulose, 1942; cuid2723 (Box 11, Folder 28)
    - A Statistical Treatment of Crystallization Phenomena in High Polymers, 1942; cuid2724 (Box 11, Folder 29)
    - Phase Transition and Elastic Bahavior of High Polymers, 1942; cuid2725 (Box 11, Folder 30)
    - Intermolecular Forces and Mechanical Behavior of High Polymers, 1942; cuid2726 (Box 11, Folder 31)
    - Stickiness, Tackiness, and Spinnability, 1942 April 1; cuid2727 (Box 11, Folder 32)
    - Improved X-Ray Technique for the Study of Natural and Synthetic Fibers, 1943 July-October; cuid2728 (Box 11, Folder 33)
    - Osmotic Pressure and Viscosity Measurements with Cellulose Acetate Fractions, 1943; cuid2729 (Box 11, Folder 34)
    - On the Mechanism of Inhibition of Styrene Polymerization, 1943 November; cuid2730 (Box 11, Folder 35)
    - Comparative Osmotic and Viscosity Measurements with Polystyrene Fractions, 1943; cuid2731 (Box 11, Folder 36)
    - Recent Results on the Kinetics and Elementary Steps of Polyreactions, 1943 November 12; cuid2732 (Box 11, Folder 37)
    - Some Scientific Aspects of the Synthetic Rubber Problem, 1943 April; cuid2733 (Box 11, Folder 38)
    - X-Ray Studies of Chain Polymers, 1944 April; cuid2734 (Box 11, Folder 39)
    - Molecular-Size Distribution of Cross-Linked Polystyrene, 1945; cuid2735 (Box 11, Folder 40)
    - Polymerization of Olefins and Diolefins in Suspension and Emulsion. Part I, 1946; cuid2736 (Box 11, Folder 41)
    - Polymerization of Olefins and Diolefins in Suspension and Emulsion. Part II, 1946; cuid2737 (Box 11, Folder 42)
    - Creep Behavior of Plasticized Vinylite VYNW, 1947; cuid2738 (Box 11, Folder 43)
    - Rate of Exchange of Cellulose with Heavy Water, 1948; cuid2739 (Box 11, Folder 44)
    - Molecular Weight Investigation of High Polymers with the Electron Microscope, 1949; cuid2740 (Box 11, Folder 45)
    - Osmotic Measurements of Isomeric Polyvinyl Isobutyl Ethers, 1949; cuid2741 (Box 11, Folder 46)
    - Viskositat und Molekulargewicht makromolekularer Losungen, 1949; cuid2742 (Box 11, Folder 47)
    - Copolymerization, 1950; cuid2743 (Box 11, Folder 48)
    - Monatshefte für Cheme, 1950; cuid2744 (Box 11, Folder 49)
    - Inhibition of Friedel-Crafts Polymerization. 1. The Mechanism of Inhibition, 1950; cuid2745 (Box 11, Folder 50)
    - The Effect of Oxygen on the Physical and Chemical Properties of Polymers, 1950; cuid2746 (Box 11, Folder 51)
    - Biological Significance of Folding and Unfolding Protein Molecules, 1951 May 5; cuid2747 (Box 11, Folder 52)
    - Synthesis of Macromolecules with Long Range Periodicities, 1951; cuid2748 (Box 11, Folder 53)
    - Mischpolymerisation II, 1951 November 15; cuid2749 (Box 11, Folder 54)
    - Osmotic, Viscometric, and Turbidity Studies of Polystyrene in Mixed Solvents, March 1951; cuid2750 (Box 11, Folder 55)
    - High Temperature Osmometry of Polymer Solution, 1952; cuid2751 (Box 11, Folder 56)
    - Report on the Shear Dependence of the Intrinsic Viscosity of Cellulose Nitrate Solutions, 1952 April 14; cuid2752 (Box 11, Folder 57)
    - Viskositätszahl-Molekulargewichts-Beziehung Für Cellulose Und Untersuchungen Von Nitrocellulose in Verschieden Lösungsmitteln, 1952; cuid2753 (Box 11, Folder 58)
    - Effect of Strains on Heat Distortion, 1953 November; cuid2754 (Box 11, Folder 59)
    - Report on Molecular-Weight Measurements of Standard Polystyrene Samples, 1953 February; cuid2755 (Box 11, Folder 60)
    - The Production of Organic Free Radicals by Light, 1953; cuid2756 (Box 11, Folder 61)
    - The Synthesis and Applicability of Block and Graft Copolymers, 1953; cuid2757 (Box 11, Folder 62)
    - New Types of Membranes for Osmotic Pressure Measurements, 1954; cuid2758 (Box 11, Folder 63)
    - Molecular Engineer, 1955; cuid2759 (Box 11, Folder 64)
    - Über Pfropf-und Block-Mischpolymere Aus Synthetische und Natürlichen Makromolekülen, 1955; cuid2760 (Box 11, Folder 65)
    - Makromolekule mit mehreren Bindungsarten, 1955; cuid2761 (Box 11, Folder 66)
    - Nuove gomme, nuove materie plastiche e nuove fibre, 1955 January; cuid2762 (Box 11, Folder 67)
    - Prof. Kurt G. Stern, 1956 March 24; cuid2763 (Box 11, Folder 68)
    - Radiation Chemistry and Wood, 1956 April 8-13; cuid2764 (Box 11, Folder 69)
    - Synthesis of Vinyl Type Polymers with Coordination Catalysts, 1956; cuid2765 (Box 11, Folder 70)
    - Theorie und Molekulare Deutung Technologischer Eigenschaften von Hochpolymerer Werkstoffen, 1956; cuid2766 (Box 11, Folder 71)
    - Organic Plastics as Conductors and Semiconductors, 1957; cuid2767 (Box 11, Folder 72)
    - Losungseigenschaften isotaktischer Polymerer, 1957; cuid2768 (Box 11, Folder 73)
    - A Few Principles of Adhesion, 1957; cuid2769 (Box 11, Folder 74)
    - Giant Molecules, 1957; cuid2770 (Box 11, Folder 75)
    - Progress in the Field of High Polymers, 1957; cuid2771 (Box 11, Folder 76)
    - Soviet Polymer Science Today, 1958 July; cuid2772 (Box 11, Folder 77)
    - A Convenient Laboratory Preperation of Isotactic Polystyrene, 1959; cuid2773 (Box 11, Folder 78)
    - Fortschritte auf dem Gebiet der Hochpolymeren in USA, 1959; cuid2774 (Box 11, Folder 79)
    - Thermisch Resistente Polymere, 1960; cuid2775 (Box 11, Folder 80)
    - Sonderdruck Aus Der Zeitschrift>>Kunststoffe, 1960; cuid2776 (Box 11, Folder 81)
    - Recent Developments in the Field of High Polymers, 1960; cuid2777 (Box 11, Folder 82)
    - Cleavage of Disulfide Polymers. I. By Inorganic Sulfides*, 1961; cuid2778 (Box 11, Folder 83)
    - Künftige Entwicklungsrichtlinien zur Verbesserung der Kohäsionsund Adhäsionsfestigkeit von Polymeren, 1962; cuid2779 (Box 11, Folder 84)
    - Future Trends For Improvement of Ashesive Strength of Polymers, 1962; cuid2780 (Box 11, Folder 85)
    - New Resins for Electrical Applications, 1962; cuid2781 (Box 11, Folder 86)
    - Future Trends for Improvement of Cohesive and Adhesive Strength of Polymers, 1962; cuid2782 (Box 11, Folder 87)
    - Inhibition of Radical Polymerization in Liquid Sulfer Dioxide by Alkali Iodide and Dimethylsuldoxide, 1962; cuid2783 (Box 11, Folder 88)
    - Structure and Properties of Polymeric Materials, 1963; cuid2784 (Box 11, Folder 89)
    - Cleavage of Disulfide Polymers. II. By Thiols*, 1963; cuid2785 (Box 11, Folder 90)
    - Report on our Observations of South American Countries, 1964; cuid2786 (Box 11, Folder 91)
    - Synthesis and Application of New Polymers, 1964; cuid2787 (Box 11, Folder 92)
    - Polymers- Past, Present, Future, 1964; cuid2788 (Box 11, Folder 93)
    - Tailor-Making Plastics, 1964; cuid2789 (Box 11, Folder 94)
    - Stereospecific Polymerization, 1965; cuid2790 (Box 11, Folder 95)
    - Report on Copolymerization, 1965; cuid2791 (Box 11, Folder 96)
    - Techniques de L'ingenieur, 1965; cuid2792 (Box 11, Folder 97)
    - Polymere Als Baumaterialien, 1966; cuid2793 (Box 11, Folder 98)
    - New Concepts - New Polymers - New Applications, 1967; cuid2794 (Box 11, Folder 99)
    - The Nature of Polymeric Materials, 1967; cuid2795 (Box 11, Folder 100)
    - Some Quantitative Consideration on Spinning, 1967; cuid2796 (Box 11, Folder 101)
    - Synthetic Polymers in Medical Sciences, 1968; cuid2797 (Box 11, Folder 102)
    - Fibras De Celulosa, 1968; cuid2798 (Box 11, Folder 103)
    - Polymer Science in the Prevention of Air Pollution, 1969; cuid2799 (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - Diffusion and Reaction of Polymers in a Capillary Matrix, 1969; cuid2800 (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - Some Quantitative Considerations on Spinning, 1970; cuid2801 (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - Bulletinul Institutului Politechnic, 1970; cuid2802 (Box 12, Folder 4)
    - Vortragszyklus-Umweltschutz, 1971; cuid2803 (Box 12, Folder 5)
    - Polymeric Conductors and Semiconductors, 1972; cuid2804 (Box 12, Folder 6)
    - What Next in Man-Made Fibers?, 1972; cuid2805 (Box 12, Folder 7)
    - The Early Days of Polymer Science, 1973; cuid2806 (Box 12, Folder 8)
    - Quantitative Betrachtungen Uber Das Schmelzspinnen, 1973; cuid2807 (Box 12, Folder 9)
    - Discursos Del Acto De La Solemne Investidura de Doctores, 1974; cuid2808 (Box 12, Folder 10)
    - Polymers in the Next Decade, 1974; cuid2809 (Box 12, Folder 11)
    - Polymeric Materials: Natural and Synthetic, 1974; cuid2810 (Box 12, Folder 12)
    - Contemporary Topics in Polymer Sciences, 1974; cuid2811 (Box 12, Folder 13)
    - Visit to China in June, 1972, 1974; cuid2812 (Box 12, Folder 14)
    - Polymers in the Next Decades, 1974; cuid2813 (Box 12, Folder 15)
    - Aromatic Polymers, 1974; cuid2814 (Box 12, Folder 16)
    - Combustion of Polymers and its Retardation, 1975; cuid2815 (Box 12, Folder 17)
    - Komfort und Hygiene der Kleidung(Cernia, Mark, Atlas), cuid2816 (Box 12, Folder 18)
    - Polymer Progress--Worldwide, 1975; cuid2817 (Box 12, Folder 19)
    - Polimery Organiczne a Srodowisko, 1975; cuid2818 (Box 12, Folder 20)
    - Verfahrenstechnik Technische Chemie Apparatewesen, 1975; cuid2819 (Box 12, Folder 21)
    - Current Developments for Polymeric Materials, 1976; cuid2820 (Box 12, Folder 22)
    - Cellulose- Past, Present and Future, 1976; cuid2821 (Box 12, Folder 23)
    - Polymers as Building Materials, 1976; cuid2822 (Box 12, Folder 24)
    - Polymers as Materials, 1976; cuid2823 (Box 12, Folder 25)
    - Catalysis in Polymerization, 1976; cuid2824 (Box 12, Folder 26)
    - Introduction to Polymer Science, 1977; cuid2825 (Box 12, Folder 27)
    - Contemporary Topics in Polymer Science Volume I Macromolecular Science Retrospect and Prospect, cuid2826 (Box 12, Folder 28)
    - Reprint From Proceedings of the 5th European Symposium on Polymer Spectroscopy in Cologn, September 78, 1978; cuid2827 (Box 12, Folder 29)
    - Polymers for the Future, 1978; cuid2828 (Box 12, Folder 30)
    - So Plannten Wir Den Aufbau des Weizmann-Institus[The Planning of the Weizmann Institute], 1980; cuid2829 (Box 12, Folder 31)
    - Fifty Years of Cellulose Research, 1980; cuid2830 (Box 12, Folder 32)
    - Aus den Fruhen Tagen der Makromolekularen Chemie, 1980; cuid2831 (Box 12, Folder 33)
    - Why Perkin Succeeded: Perkin Medal Address, 1980; cuid2832 (Box 12, Folder 34)
    - Rehovot, 1980; cuid2833 (Box 12, Folder 35)
    - Cellulose Chemistry and Technology, 1980; cuid2834 (Box 12, Folder 36)
    - Macromolecular Chemistry Today-Aging Roots, Sprouting Branches, 1981; cuid2835 (Box 12, Folder 37)
    - Chemical Education, 1981; cuid2836 (Box 12, Folder 38)
    - Coming to an Age of Polymers in Science and Technology, 1981; cuid2837 (Box 12, Folder 39)
    - Polymers for Extreme Service Conditions, 1981; cuid2838 (Box 12, Folder 40)
    - Principles of Elastomer Synthesis, 1984; cuid2839 (Box 12, Folder 41)
    - Chemtech, 1984; cuid2840 (Box 12, Folder 42)
    - The Development of Plastics, 1984; cuid2841 (Box 12, Folder 43)
    - New Elastomers by Choice, Not Chance, 1984; cuid2842 (Box 12, Folder 44)
    - A Century of Polymer Science and Technology, 1985; cuid2843 (Box 12, Folder 45)
    - A Tale of Two Fibers: A Productive Interaction of Physics and Chemistry, 1985; cuid2844 (Box 12, Folder 46)
    - Textile and Engineering: Present and Future, 1987; cuid2845 (Box 12, Folder 47)
    - Applied Polymer Science - A Forecast, 1987; cuid2846 (Box 12, Folder 48)
    - Polymers to the Year 2000 and Beyond: A Forecast, 1988; cuid2847 (Box 12, Folder 49)
    - Polymers in Materials Science, 1990; cuid2848 (Box 12, Folder 50)
    - Advanced Materials, 1990; cuid2849 (Box 12, Folder 51)
    - Corrections of Some Miscommunications on the Development and Present Status of Rubber Elasticity (Guth+Mark), 1990; cuid2850 (Box 13, Folder 1)
    - Cellulose Chemistry and Technology, 1990; cuid2851 (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Subseries C: Articles about Herman Mark
    - Chemical and Engineering News, 1948 Novermber 1; cuid2852 (Box 13, Folder 3)
    - Molecular Engineer, 1955 April 2; cuid2853 (Box 13, Folder 4)
    - Polymers Everywhere I inThe New Yorker (with correspondence), 1958 September 13; 1957 October 2; cuid2854 (Box 13, Folder 5)
    - The New Yorker Sept. 20, 1957 with Polymers Everywhere II, 1958 September 20; cuid2855 (Box 13, Folder 6)
    - Polymers Everywhere I & II, pasted on paper, 1958; cuid2856 (Box 13, Folder 7)
    - Great American Scientists: The Chemists in Fortune Magazine, 1960 April; cuid2857 (Box 13, Folder 8)
    - Great American Scientists: The Chemists in Fortune Magazine (oversize copy), 1960 April; cuid2858 (Box 13, Folder 9)
    - Plastic Pioneer in New York Post, 1975 April 30; cuid2859 (Box 13, Folder 10)
    - A Declaration in The Chemist, 1976 July; cuid2860 (Box 13, Folder 11)
    - Harvey Prizes to Chemist and Talmudic Scholar, 1976 June 21; cuid2861 (Box 13, Folder 12)
    - Zur Geschichte der makromolekularen Chemie, 1979; cuid2862 (Box 13, Folder 13)
    - Polymersymposien, 1980; cuid2863 (Box 13, Folder 14)
    - Pioneers of Polymers, 1981; cuid2864 (Box 13, Folder 15)
    - Expert Cites Polymer "Explosion" in The Indianapolis Star, 1983 October 18; cuid2865 (Box 13, Folder 16)
    - Herman Mark and the Structure of Crystals, 1984 June; cuid2866 (Box 13, Folder 17)
    - That Was The War in The New Yorker, 1985 August 12; cuid2867 (Box 13, Folder 18)
    - Polymer Pioneer Herman Mark Wins Case's Top Science Award, 1989 April 29; cuid2868 (Box 13, Folder 19)
    - Brooklyn Poly's Mark: Master of molecules, undated; cuid2869 (Box 13, Folder 20)
    - Significant Contributions of H. Mark in Polymer Science, undated; cuid2870 (Box 13, Folder 21)
    - Newspaper clippings and photocopies, 1963-1989; 1966-1969; cuid2871 (Box 13, Folder 22)
  - Subseries D: Polymers and plastics
    - "Uber Polymerisation" by H. Staudinger, 1920; cuid2872 (Box 13, Folder 23)
    - "Zur Kenntnis der Cellulose" by K. Freudenberg, 1921 February 9; cuid2873 (Box 13, Folder 24)
    - "Uber hochpolymere Verbindungen" by H. Staudinger and W. Heuer, 1929 December; cuid2874 (Box 13, Folder 25)
    - "The New Breed of Plastics" by F. Bello, 1957 November; cuid2875 (Box 13, Folder 26)
    - "The Nylon Rope Trick: Demonstration of Condensation Polymerization" by P. Morgan and S. Kwolek, 1959 April; cuid2876 (Box 13, Folder 27)
    - Polymer Symposia No. 6: Thermal Analysis of High Polymers, 1963 September; cuid2877 (Box 13, Folder 28)
    - "Von Emmil Fischer zur molekularen Konstitution der Cellulose und Starke" by K. Freudenberg, 1967; cuid2878 (Box 13, Folder 29)
    - "Final Report on Man-Made Fiber Industry in Taiwan" by E. Braunsteiner, 1968-1969; cuid2879 (Box 13, Folder 30)
    - "Petrochemistry and the Man-Made Fibre Industry in the Developing Countries" by E. Braunsteiner, 1969 October 31; cuid2880 (Box 13, Folder 31)
    - "Final Report on Modern Polymer Science and Technology of Polyvinyl Chloride" by E. Braunsteiner, 1970; cuid2881 (Box 13, Folder 32)
    - "A Comparison of Some Electrophotographic Processes Based on Photoconductor-Insulation Layer Combinations" by P. Mark, 1974 May/June; cuid2882 (Box 13, Folder 33)
    - Request from the Government of India for the production of synthetic fibres (Nylon and Polyester), circa 1974; cuid2883 (Box 13, Folder 34)
    - "Rayon: Veteran Fiber is 'in' Again" and other articles on engineered fibers in Chemicalweek, 1979 June 6; cuid2884 (Box 13, Folder 35)
    - Commemorazione del membro effettivo Giulio Natta, 1980; cuid2885 (Box 13, Folder 36)
    - DuPont's Group Transfer Polymerization (with correspondence and press release), 1983 August 31; cuid2886 (Box 13, Folder 37)
    - DuPont Group Transfer Polymerization chemical sketches and transparencies, 1983; cuid2887 (Box 13, Folder 38)
    - DuPont Group Transfer Polymerization articles, 1983; cuid2888 (Box 13, Folder 39)
    - "Polymer Chemistry - Where Are We Going?" by M.L. Good, 1985 October 24; cuid2889 (Box 13, Folder 40)
    - Reprints from the Encyclopedia of Materials Science and Engineering, 1986; cuid2890 (Box 13, Folder 41)
    - Polymer symposia, 1986, 1992; cuid2891 (Box 13, Folder 42)
    - "The Nylon Drama" by D. Hounshell and J. Smith, 1988; cuid2892 (Box 13, Folder 43)
    - "Chemical and Mechanical Evaluation on Healing Mechanism of Asphalt Concrete" by Y. R. Kim, 1989 October; cuid2893 (Box 13, Folder 44)
    - "Strong Growth for Reinforcing Fibres" by S. Davies, 1990 January; cuid2894 (Box 13, Folder 45)
    - "Signs Point to Slowdown for European Chemical Industry in 1990", 1990 March 5; cuid2895 (Box 13, Folder 46)
    - "Conductive Polymers" M. Kanatzidis, 1990 December 3; cuid2896 (Box 13, Folder 47)
    - "Pressure for Plastic Recycling Prompts a Mix of Tough Laws and Cooperation" by R. Smith, 1990; cuid2897 (Box 13, Folder 48)
    - Polymers for Advanced Technologies, 1990; cuid2898 (Box 13, Folder 49)
    - GE Plastics: Living Environments brochures, circa 1990; cuid2899 (Box 13, Folder 50)
    - Advances in Degradable Polymers - International Herman F. Mark Symposium, 1992; cuid2900 (Box 13, Folder 51)
    - History and etymology of polymers and plastics, 1994, 2003; cuid2901 (Box 13, Folder 52)
    - Eli Pearce, 2002; cuid2902 (Box 13, Folder 53)
    - Polyethylene, undated; cuid2903 (Box 13, Folder 54)
    - "A History of Polyolefins" by H. Sailors and J. Hogan, undated; cuid2904 (Box 13, Folder 55)
    - Sections VII and VIII on Staudinger and Farben by Udo Tschimmel, undated; cuid2905 (Box 13, Folder 56)
    - SWP synthetic fiber from Crown Zellerbach, undated; cuid2906 (Box 13, Folder 57)
    - Chapter 8: Aliphatic Polyethers, by S. Inoue and T. Aida, undated; cuid2907 (Box 13, Folder 58)
    - Chapter 10: Poly(acetal)s, by H. Gorrisen, undated; cuid2908 (Box 13, Folder 59)
    - Book section in German (title unknown), undated; cuid2909 (Box 13, Folder 60)
    - Articles on microfiche, undated; cuid2910 (Box 13, Folder 61)
  - Subseries E: Physics and chemistry
    - "Abstract Vector Spaces Applied to Problems in Detection and Estimation Theory" by M. Schwartz, 1966 July; cuid2911 (Box 13, Folder 62)
    - Great Moments in Chemistry, 1969 April; cuid2912 (Box 13, Folder 63)
    - "Facts and Figures for Chemical R&D" by B. Hileman, 1990 August 20; cuid2913 (Box 13, Folder 64)
    - "Unified Theories of Elementary-Particle Interaction" by S. Weinberg, undated; cuid2914 (Box 13, Folder 65)
    - "The Use of the Method of Maximum Likelihood in Estimating Continuous-Modulated Intelligence which has been Corrupted by Noise" by D. Youla, undated; cuid2915 (Box 13, Folder 66)
  - Subseries F: Hans Mark
    - Publications by Hans Mark, 1981-2004; 1981-1988; cuid2916 (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - Sixty Years of Polymers in Brooklyn (transparencies), undated; cuid2917 (Box 14, Folder 2)
    - Hans Mark and Polytechnic, 2007, undated; cuid2918 (Box 14, Folder 3)
    - Interviews with and articles about Hans Mark, 1984-1990; cuid2919 (Box 14, Folder 4)
    - Trade publications, 1981-1988; cuid2920 (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Subseries G: Monographs and notebooks
    - H.F.M Diary, 1950; cuid2921 (Box 15, Item 1)
    - Mark address book, undated; cuid2922 (Box 15, Item 2)
    - Mark address book, undated; cuid2923 (Box 15, Item 3)
    - "Formelsammlung und Repetitorium der Mathematik," by O. Burklen, 1918; cuid2924 (Box 15, Item 4)
    - Various German articles, bound, 1924; cuid2925 (Box 15, Item 5)
    - Various German articles, bound, undated; cuid2926 (Box 15, Item 6)
    - Various German articles, bound (articles numbered by Mark), undated; cuid2927 (Box 15, Item 7)
    - "The Phenomena of Polymerisation and Condensation: A General Discussion," by The Faraday Society, 1936; cuid2928 (Box 15, Item 8)
    - "Collected Papers of Wallance Hume Carothers on High Polymeric Substances" ed. by H. Mark and G. Whitby, 1940; cuid2929 (Box 15, Item 9)
    - "Advances in Colloid Science, Volume II" ed. by H. Mark and G. Whitby, 1946; cuid2930 (Box 15, Item 10)
    - "Advances in Colloid Science, Volume III" ed. by H. Mark and E Verwey, 1950; cuid2931 (Box 15, Item 12)
    - "Etat Acuel de la Chimie et de la Physique des Molecules Geantes" by H. Mark, 1950; cuid2932 (Box 15, Item 13)
    - "Polymer Reviews" by N. Gaylord and H. Mark, 1959; cuid2933 (Box 15, Item 14)
    - "Condensation Polymers: Interfacial and Solution Methods" by P. Morgan, 1965; cuid2934 (Box 15, Item 15)
    - Offprint from Perspectives in American History, Volume II, 1968; cuid2935 (Box 15, Item 16)
    - "Flame -Retardant Polymeric Materials" Ed. by M. Lewin, S. Atlas, and E. Pearce, 1978; cuid2936 (Box 15, Item 17)